Guide to the Edward Lee Plumb Papers, 1856-1912
Department of Special Collections
- CORRESPONDENCE 1877, January - March (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - 19. Feb. 11.W.H. Hurlbert to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 20. Feb. 12.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada., Tel.
  - 21. Feb. 12.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L.P., Tel. in Sp.
  - 22. Feb. 16 (rcvd).Wm. H. Hurlbert to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. Feb. 16.E.L.P. to Wm. H. Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 24. Feb. 17.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 25. Feb. 17.E.L.P. to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 26. Feb. 18.E.L.P. to Albert H. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 27. Feb. 24 (rcvd).W.H. Hurlbert to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 28. Feb. 24.E.L.P. to W.H. Hurlbert., A.L.S.
  - 29. Feb. 27.E.L.P. to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 30. Mar. 5.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 31. Mar. 6.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P. Hayes election., A.L.S.
  - 32. Mar. 6 & Mar. 3.Extracts from ltrs. re: Diaz regime.
  - 33. [1877], Mar. 8.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 34. Mar. 15.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 35. Mar. 16.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 36. Mar. 16.Extract from letter from Mexico, Diaz regime.
  - 37. Mar. 18.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 38. Mar. 19.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 39. Mar. 19.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 40. Mar. 23.E.L.P. to Geo. W. Brackridge., A.L.S.
  - 41. Mar. 23.E.L.P. to E.O.C. Ord., A.L.S.
  - 42. Mar. 24.E.L.P. to E.O.C. Ord., A.L.S.
  - 43. Mar. 24.E.L.P. to F.W. Seward., A.L.S.
  - 44. Mar. 26.E.L.P. to R.S. Hayes. Texas RRs., A.L.S.
  - 45. Mar. 27.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 46. Mar. 27.E.L.P. to John L. Geiger., A.L.S.
  - 47. Mar. 30.T.W. Pierce to Benj. E. Bates., Copy of ltr.
  - 48. Mar. 30.E.L.P. to R.C. McCormick., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1877, April - May (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - 1. Apr. 4.E.L.P. to S. Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 2. Apr. 5.D.P. [Barhydt] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 3. Apr. 5.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 4. Apr. 9.E.L.P. to R.C. McCormick., A.L.S.
  - 5. Apr. 10.E.L.P. to Benj. E. Bates., A.L.S.
  - 6. Apr. 10.E.L.P. to C.P. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 7. Apr. 10.E.L.P. to T.W. Pierce., A.L.S.
  - 8. Apr. 10.E.L.P. to C. Sligo de Pothonier., A.L.S.
  - 9. Apr. 11.C.P. Mackie to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 10. Apr. 11.C.P. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. Apr. 11.E.L.P. to R.C. McCormick., A.L.S.
  - 12. Apr. 11.E.L.P. to C.P. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 13. Apr. 12.E.L.P. to C.P. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 14. Apr. 13.Edw. Atkinson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. Apr. 13.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 16. Apr. 13.E.L.P. to Henry C. Hall. U.S. foreign policy., A.L.S.
  - 17. Apr. 20.S. Lerdo de Tejada to Thomas A. Scott., L. (copy) in Sp.
  - 18. Apr. 21.E.L.P. to Frank S. Bond., A.L.S.
  - 19. Apr. 21.E.L.P. to Albert H. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 20. Apr. 23.Frank S. Bond to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. Apr. 23.E.L.P. to Edw. Atkinson., A.L.S.
  - 22. Apr. 23.E.L.P. to [Thomas H.] Nelson, A.L.S.
  - 23. Apr. 23.E.L.P. to Thomas A. Scott., A.L.S.
  - 24. Apr. 24.Mariano Escobedo to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 25. Apr. 27.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 26. Apr. 27.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 27. Apr. 28.in Sp. M. de Zamacona to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 28. May 2.John N. Goodwin to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 29. May 2.E.L.P. to R.C. McCormick., A.L.S.
  - 30. May 4.in Sp. M. Escobedo to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 31. May 4.E.L.P. to Edw. Atkinson. Cotton shipments to Mexico., A.L.S.
  - 32. May 5.Edw. Atkinson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 33. May 7.H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 34. May 9.S Lerdo de Tejada to E.L.P., L.S. in Sp.
  - 35. May 10.E.L.P. to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 36. May 11.E.L.P. to Mariano Escobedo., A.L.S.
  - 37. May 19.Chas. Sligo de Pothonier to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 38. May 25.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1877, June - December (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - 1. June 15.Mariano Escobedo to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 2. June 16.C. Sligo de Pothonier to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 3. Aug. 11.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 4. Aug. 15.E.L.P. to Ira H. Evans., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 5. Aug. 20.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 6. Aug. 22.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 7. Aug. 29.C.C. Gibbs to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 8. Sep. 1.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 9. Sep. 1.Warren Delano to E.L.P., A.L.S. in Sp.
  - 10. Oct. 8.Thomas H. Nelson to E.L.P., L. (copy). (Torn original inside).
  - 11. Oct. 9.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. An Atlantic - Pacific canal., A.L.S.
  - 12. Oct. 11.E.L.P. to Thomas H. Nelson. U.S. - Mexican commerce, Sonora's threatened succession, Diaz & regime., A.L.S.
  - 13. Oct. 16.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 14. Oct. 22.Edw. Atkinson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. Oct. 26.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. A Nicaragua Canal., A.L.S.
  - 16. Nov. 6.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 17. & 18. Nov. 10.Memo & copy to Mr. Rogers purporting to state terms of a Mexican concession claimed to be held by Renan & Co.
  - 19. Dec. 12.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. - 22. RR. projects for Mexico., Notes & clips.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1878, January - July (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - 1. Jan. 11.G.Y. Tobey to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 2. Jan. 16.Estanislao Canedo to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 3. Jan. 28.in Sp. Mariano Escobedo to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 4. Feb. 9.Lizzie L. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 5. Feb. 25.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 6. Feb. 25.James S. Mackie to E.L.P. Navy - Amazon exploring expedition., A.L.S.
  - 7. Mar. 2.Moses Taylor to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. Mar. 17.E.L.P. to R.C. McCormick., A.L.S.
  - 9. Mar. 19.R. C. McCormick to E.L.P. Universal Exposition of 1878 at Paris., A.L.S.
  - 10. Mar. 22.D.W. McWilliams to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. Apr. 19.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P. Cuban situation., A.L.S.
  - 12. May 1.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., Ptd. announcement.
  - 13. May 1.E.L.P. to Thomas A. Scott., A.L.S.
  - 14. May 2.Thomas A. Scott to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 15. May 3.C.C. Gibbs to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 16. May 24.[George Wilson] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 17. May 29.E.L.P. to U.S. Grant. Mexican situation, U.S. recognition of Diaz., A.L.S.
  - 18. June 6.[George Wilson] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 19. June 10.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. June 10.H. G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. June 14.E.L.P. to J.S. Wetmore., A.L.S.
  - 22. June 15.Jacob S. Wetmore to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. June 20.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 24. June 27.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. July 9.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 26. July 18.E.L.P. to Alvah A. Clark., A.L.S.
  - 27. July 27.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1878, August - December (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - 1. Aug. 6.[E.L.P.] to Geo. E. Church., A.L.
  - 2. Aug. 7.F.W. Seward to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 3. Aug. 13.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 4. Aug. 13.E.L.P. to F.W. Seward., A.L.S.
  - 5. Aug. 19.G. Schleicher to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 6. Aug. 24.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 7. Aug. 28.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. Aug. 30.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 9. Sep. 8.Jno. H. Flagg to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. Sep. 8.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. Sep. 9.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. Amazon RR., A.L.S.
  - 12. Sep. 9.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 13. Sep. 14.H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 14. Sep. 17.E.L.P. to John N. Goodwin. Land patents., A.L.S.
  - 15. Sep. 18.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 16. Sep. [19].G. Schleicher to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 17. Sep. 20.Jas. Stewart Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 18. Sep. 25.E.L.P. to Wm. M. Evarts., A.L.S.
  - 19. Oct. 5.E.L.P. to Guillermo Martinez. U.S. - Cuba commercial relations., A.L.S.
  - 20. Oct. 7.Guillermo Martinez to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. Oct. 7.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 22. Oct. 8.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. [Oct. 9].U.S. - Mexico commercial relations., Copy of Res.
  - 24. Oct. 14.J. Steuart Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. Oct. 16.Knowlton & Co. to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 26. Oct. 17.E.L.P. to G. Schleicher., A.L.S.
  - 27. Oct. 19.John N. Goodwin to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 28. Oct. 21.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 29. Oct. 21.H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 30. Nov. 9.John N. Goodwin to E.L.P. Washington Territory, Cowlitz pass, RR., A.L.S.
  - 31. Nov. 11.J.E. Gates to J.H. Flagg., A.L.S.
  - 32. Nov. 12.J.H. Flagg to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 33. Nov. 13.H.W. Bates to [Geo. E.] Church., A.L.S.
  - 34. Nov. 14.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 35. Nov. 14.H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 36. Nov. 17.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 37. Nov. 18.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 38. Nov. 18.E.L.P. to W. Milnor Roberts, A.L.S.
  - 39. Nov. 19.Geo. W. Brackenridge to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 40. Nov. 19.E.L.P. to James S. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 41. Nov. 20.E.L.P. to Thomas Allen., A.L.S.
  - 42. Nov. 20.E.L.P. to Chas. Babbidge., A.L.S.
  - 43. Nov. 21.E.L.P. to Chas. Babbidge., A.L.S.
  - 44. Nov. 23.Chas. Babbidge to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 45. Nov. 25.E.L.P. to Chas. Babbidge., A.L.S.
  - 46. Nov. 28.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 47. Dec. 10.D.W. McWilliams to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 48. Dec. 12.E.L.P. to Chas. Babbidge., A.L.S.
  - 49. Dec. 13.Chas. Babbidge to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 50. Dec. 14.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 51. Dec. 18.J.S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 52. Dec. 20.Medical Society of the District of Columbia to E.L.P., Ptd. invitation.
  - 53. Dec. 21.John N. Goodwin to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 54. Dec. 21.E.L.P. to [John N. Goodwin], A.L.S.
  - 55. Dec. 23.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 56. Dec. 25.John N. Goodwin to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 57. Dec. 26.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 58. Dec. 27.T.W. Peirce to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 59. Dec. 28.H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 60. Dec. 31.E.L.P. to Geo. W. Brackenridge., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1879 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - 1. Jan. 16.John W. Foster to E.L.P. Death of Schleicher., A.L.S.
  - 2. Jan. 16.John W. Foster to D.W. Voorhees., A.L.S.
  - 3. Jan. 17.H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 4. Jan. 27.Mr. & Mrs. A.R. Spofford to E.L.P., A.N.
  - 5. Jan. 30.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 6. Feb. 9.Hyde Clarke to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 7. Feb. 18.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. Feb. 26.Richard S. Spofford to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 9. Feb. 27.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. Feb.Ellen Wood to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. Mar. 10.Thomas H. Nelson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 12. & 13. Mar. 14.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., 2 A.L.S.
  - 14. Mar. 16.Jos. C. Audenreid to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. Mar. 18.Jno. H. Flagg to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 16. Mar. 18.[Alex. McDowell McCook]., A.L.S.
  - 17. Mar. 21.T.F. Dwight, to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 18. Apr. 2.[S.N. Petris?] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 19. Apr. 9.John W. Foster to E.L.P. Resignation of Romero, etc., A.L.S.
  - 20. Apr. 29.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. May 17.S.F. Union Club to E.L.P., Ptd. N.
  - 22. June 2.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. June 12.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 24. June 12.H.G. Marquand to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. June 16.C.H. Lord to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 26. June 27.E.L.P. to A.E. Burnside., A.L.S.
  - 27. June 29.A.E. Burnside to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 28. June 30.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 29. July 9Chas. A. Wetmore to [E.L.P.], A.L.S.
  - 30. Aug. 5.P.B. Plumb to Van [Magenin?]., A.N.S.
  - 31. Aug. 20.W.P. Blake to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 32. Aug. 20.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 33. Aug. 28.[illegible] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 34. Sep. 2.Nath. Paige to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 35. Sep. 5.H.G. Marquand, to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 36. Sep. 8. &cvr. John W. Foster to E.L.P. Mexican affairs, RRs., mining., A.L.S.
  - 37. Sep. 15.W.P. Blake to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 38. Sep. 27.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., L.S.
    re:CUBAN AFFAIRS
  - 39. Sep. 30.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 40. Oct. 8.Albert H. Plumb to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 41. Oct. 29.Jos. C. Audenreid to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 42. Nov. 1.Orlando Metcalf Poe to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 43. Nov. 17.B.W. Mudge to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 44. Nov. 26.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 45. Dec. 10.W.P. Blake to E.L.P., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1880 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - 1. Jan. 10.W.P. Blake to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 2. Jan. 24.John W. Foster to E.L.P. Mexican affairs., A.L.S.
  - 3. May 13.R.S. Spofford to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 4. June 3.Ptd. D. Gen. Orders No 45. Death & biolgraphy of Joseph Crain Audenried.
  - 5. June 7.E.L.P. to Thomas M. Drown., A.L.S.
  - 6. June 8.Thomas M. Drown to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 7. June 10.Gurdon H. Wilcox to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. June 12.E.L.P. to Gurdon H. Wilcox., A.L.S.
  - 9. July 24.Virginia Stuart to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. July 24.Watson, Phillips & Co. to E.L.P. Auction of Mr. Foster's furniture., A.L.S.
  - 11. July 28.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 12. Aug. 30.John W. Foster to E.L.P. At St. Petersburg., A.L.S.
  - 13. Aug. 31.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 14. Sep. 2.International & Gt. Northern RR. Stock - Bonds - Earnings, etc., Notes & clip.
  - 15. Sep. 4.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 16. Sep. 8.Concession to Mexican Central RR., Extract in Sp.
  - 17. Sep. 9.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 18. Sep. 11.J.N. Goodwin to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 19. Sep. 11.Henry [Johnsen] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. Sep. 24.J.A. Grant to Wm. G. Fuller., L. (copy).
  - 21. Oct. 4.John H. Flagg to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 22. Oct. 7.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. Oct. 7.J.A. Grant to unknown. With Henry G. Vennen ltr. of Oct. 8, 1878. Also, clip., notes & sketch., L. (copy).
  - 24. Oct. 13.A.D. Anderson to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. Oct. 29.B.S. Henning to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 26. Nov. 4.Clinton Rice to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 27. Nov. 11.[R.M. Plumb] to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 28. Nov. 15.E.L.P. to U.S. Grant., A.L.S.
  - 29. Nov. 16.E.L.P. to U.S. Grant., A.L.S.
  - 30. Nov. 16.Report on Mine of Nuestra Senora near Casala, Mexico & notes & clips on some others., D. extract.
  - 31. Nov. 17.E.L.P. to Watson, Phillips & Co., A.L.S.
  - 32. Nov. 26.Theodore F. Dwight to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 33. Dec. 1.R.S. Hayes to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 34. Dec. 3.D.J. Morrell to E.L.P., L. (copy).
  - 35. Dec. 4.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 36. Dec. 12.G. Wm. Ballon to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 37. Dec. 21.Watson, Phillips & Co. to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 38. Dec. 30.B. Silliman to E.L.P., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1881, January - April (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - 1. Jan. 12.[T.W.] Pearsall to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 2. Jan. 12.E.G. Vernon to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 3. Jan. 13.John F. Dillon to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 4. Jan. 13.E.L.P. to Watson, Philllips & Co., A.L.S.
  - 5. Jan. 14.T.W. Pearsall to [John F.] Dillon., L. (copy).
  - 6. Jan. 15.T.W. Pearsall to E.L.P., L. (copy).
  - 7. Jan. 21.(Part in Sp. & transl.) Juan N. Navarro to T.W. Pearsall., L. (copy).
  - 8. Jan. 24.H.G. Marquand to Sebastian Camacho & Ramon G. Guzman., L. (copy).
  - 9. Jan. 25.Sam Ward to [E.L.P.?]., A.N.S.
  - 10. Jan. 27.E.L.P. to?. Mexican debt., A.L.S.
  - 11. Jan. 28.S. Ward to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 12. Jan. 31.E.L.P. to?, A.L.S.
  - 13. Jan.Misc. papers re: Mexican International Railroad.
  - 14. Feb. 2.E.L.P. to?, A.L.S.
  - 15. Feb. 4.E.L.P. to?., A.L.S.
  - 16. Feb. 8.E.L.P. to?., A.L.S.
  - 17. Feb. 9.[Levellon] A. Brown to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 18. Feb. 16.E.L.P. to?., A.L.S.
  - 19. Feb. 19.W.P. Blake to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. Feb. 19.W.J. Palmer to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 21. Apr. 8.Gen. E.O.C. Ord to C.P.H., A.L.S.
  - 22. Apr. 9.Henry C. Hall to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. Apr. 14.E.L.P. to?, A.L.S.
  - 24. Apr. 15.Gen Dewey to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. Apr. 18.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 26. Apr. 20.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. Pearce mines., A.L.S.
  - 27. Apr. 21.H.A. Mott, Jr. to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 28. Apr. 22.Edw. Hathwood to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 29. Apr. 22.From Diario Oficial & Menitor Republicano, City of Mexico, transl. Mexican debt.
  - 30. Apr. 28.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 31. Apr. 28.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., Tel.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1881, May - June (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - 1. May 5.E.L.P. to Edw. Hathwood., A.L.S.
  - 2. May 5.E.L.P. to unknown. Mexican bonds., A.L.S.
  - 3. May 17.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. Colorado Mine (Pearce)., A.L.S.
  - 4. May 22.R.S. Spofford to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 5. May 25.Edw. A. Aiken to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 6. May 25.Strickland d'Kurass to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 7. [May].T.W. Pearsall to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. June 6.T.W. Pearsall to [E.L.P.?], A.N.S.
  - 9. 1881?Geo. Wm. Bellon to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 10. [1881?].Poem Sidney Hyde. Fallen Leaves & a variation.
  - 11. [1881].Misc. papers on Mexican foreign debt.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1882, 1883, 1889, 1890, 1892, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - 1. 1882, Dec. 13.Frank Anderson to Clark [Rever]., Tel.
  - 2. 1883, May 2 - 26.Principal points of the new Mexican Southern PR concession., A.D. & df.
  - 3. 1889, Apr. 8.Collis P. Huntington to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 4. 1889, Apr. 15.E.L.P. to L.M. Johnson. Resignation from Vice Presidency of International RR., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1889, Apr. 24.[J.E. Dennison] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 6. 188-.A.L. Frag. [E.L.P.].
  - 7. 188-.Written invitation to dinner from C.P. Huntington to E. L. P. to meet General Diaz. With souvenir seating chart.
  - 8. & 9. 1890, Feb. 13.Invitation to dinner from Maison du Khedive to E.L.P., 2 cards.
  - 10. 1892, July 25.Alice Sabine-Magee to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1892, Oct. 31.Alice Sabine-Magee to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1893, Jan. 30.Alice Sabine-Magee to E.L.P., L. & A.N.S.
  - 13. 1893, Mar. 7.Margaret Sabine to E.L.P., A.L.S. With ptd. death notice of daughter.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1896, January - May (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - 1. Jan. 8.S. M. Romero to [E.L.P.]., Invit.
  - 2. Jan. 19.E.I.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.
  - 3. Jan. 20.E.I.P. to R.R. Hitt. Cuban situation., A.L.S.
  - 4. Jan. 25.E.I.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 5. Jan. 31.E.I.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 6. Feb. 3.E.I.P. to R.R. Hitt. Venezuelan boundary affair., A.L.S.
  - 7. Feb. 11.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 8. Feb. 12.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 9. Mar. 1.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 10. Mar. 5.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 11. Mar. 10.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church. Nicaragua Canal., A.L.S.
  - 12. Mar. 13.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 13. Mar. 15.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 14. Mar. 20.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 15. Mar. 22.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 16. Mar. 24.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 17. Mar. 31.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 18. Apr. 3.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 19. Apr. 10.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church. Alaska boundary line., A.L.S.
  - 20. Apr. 15.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 21. Apr. 22.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 22. May 4.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 23. May 12.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 24. May 15.E.L.P. to Geo E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 25. & 26. May 15. History of Louisiana - Spanish Domination by C. Gayarre., Extracts.
  - 27. - 29. May 26.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S. & df. & typed copy.
  - 30. May 29.E.L.P. to Richard Olney., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1896, June - December (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - 1. June 2.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 2. June 2.Notes on Cuba & Spain.
  - 3. June 9.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church. Venezuelan affair., A.L.S.
  - 4. June 15.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 5. June 15.E.L.P. to Richard Olney., A.L.S.
  - 6. June 19.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 7. June 25.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 8. - 10. June.Extract of ltr. with typed extract from History of Louisiana, Spanish Domination., (holograph & typed copies)
  - 11. July 6.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 12. July 6.E.L.P. to Richard Olney., A.L.S.
  - 13. July 7.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 14. July 24.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 15. Aug. 22.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., L.S.
  - 16. Aug. 24.Andrew D. White to E.L.P. Opinion on Venezuelan affair., T.L.S.
  - 17. Sept. 19.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S. & enclosure.
  - 18. Sep. 26.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 19. Sep. 30.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 20. Oct. 14.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 21. Oct. 30.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 22. Nov. 6.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 23. Nov. 16.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 24. Nov. 22.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 25. Nov. 28.George Earl Church to E.L.P. Hakluyt Society., A.L.S.
  - 26. Nov. 30.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White. Election, football., A.L.S.
  - 27. Dec. 9.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 28. Dec. 16.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 29. Dec. 21.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 30. [1896?].Notes on Cuba.
  - 31. & 32. [1896?].Holograph & typed copy of Spanish Domination in Louisiana.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1897, January - June (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - 1. Jan. 4.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 2. Jan. 18.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 3. Jan. 19.E.L.P. to Chas. P. Daly., A.L.S.
  - 4. Jan. 20.Gardiner G. Hubbard to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 5. Jan. 21.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 6. Jan. 21.E.L.P. to Gardiner G. Hubbard., A.L.S.
  - 7. Jan. 23.Andrew D. White to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 8. Feb. 1.William Foster to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 9. Feb. 13.Chas. P. Daly to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. Feb. 17.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. Mar. 11.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White. Arbitration Treaty., A.L.S.
  - 12. Mar. 26.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. Levant & Crete., A.L.S.
  - 13. Apr. 21.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. McKinley, party politics & names., A.L.S.
  - 14. May 10.Mary Parke Foster to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 15. May 10.Pres. & Mrs. McKinley to E.L.P., Invit. & cvr.
  - 16. May 22.Chas. P. Daly to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 17. May 24.Perry Allen to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 18. May 25. &encl. Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 19. May 26.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 20. May 27.[E.L.P.] British Honduras., Memo.
  - 21. May 28.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 22. June 2.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 23. June 3.Alex. T. Mason to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 24. June 3.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 25. June 7.Venezuela Boundary Cmm. to E.L.P., Ptd. L.
  - 26. June 12.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 27. June 25.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1897, July - December (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - 1. July 22.Venezuela Boundary Cmm. to [E.L.P.]., Ptd. L.
  - 2. Aug. 9.Illegible to E.L.P. (from Mexico)., A.L.S.
  - 3. Aug. 10.C.P. Huntington to Major R.B. Gorsuch., A.L.S. (copy).
  - 4. Sep. 14.James Stillman to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 5. Sep. 17.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 6. Sep. 21.James W. Ryland to Geo. E. Church., T.L.
  - 7. Oct. 1.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. Oct. 19.Geo. C. Hurlbut to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 9. Nov. 9.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. Nov. 10.M. Romero to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 11. Nov. 22.M. Romero to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 12. Dec. 3.Wm. Cotter Dick E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 13. Dec. 9.M. Romero to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 14. Dec. 10.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 15. Dec. 16.Wm. R. Day to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 16. Dec. 16.E.L.P. to Andrew D. White., A.L.S.
  - 17. Dec. 22.L.M. Johnson to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 18. [1897, Dec. 23].Cd. S. Geo. E. Church to E.L.P.
  - 19. Dec. 28.Geo E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. [1897].British Honduras & Mexico., Notes.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1898, January - March (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - 1. Jan. 6.M. Romero to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 2. Jan. 24.W.J. Sewell to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 3. Jan. 25.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 4. Jan. 29.Geo. C. Hurlbut to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 5. Jan. 31.E.L.P. to Chas. P. Daly., A.L.S.
  - 6. Feb. 4.Mrs. John W. Foster to [E.L.P.]., Ptd. Invit.
  - 7. Feb. 9.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day. Cuban question, acquisition of Hawaii, Isthmian Canal., A.L.S.
  - 8. Feb. 10.E.L.P. to [Wm. R.] Day., A.L.S.
  - 9. Feb. 11.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. Dreyfus case, Zola trial., A.L.S.
  - 10. Feb. 11.Extract & notes from above.
  - 11. Feb. 11.A.G. Newton to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 12. Feb. 12.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 13. Feb. 14.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 14. Feb. 18.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 15. Feb. 19.Dr. & Mrs. Mackay-Smith to E.L.P., A.N.